Finding Aid for the Pat And Lily Okura Papers LSC.2367
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 2: Minority health advocacy files, 1961-2005
  - Community Mental Health - AAPA, 1975-2005 (Box 42, Folder 1-7)
    Folders 3-4 contain newsletters. Folders 5-7 contains the AAPA Journal.
  - Community Mental Health - American Psychological Association Ethnic Minority Issues Division, 1983-2000 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    This contains a Lifetime Achievement Award presented to K. Patrick Okura at the 110th convention of the American Psychological Association in 2002.
  - Community Mental Health - American Psychological Association Peace, Gender Issues, and Social Issues Divisions, 1981-2001 (Box 43, Folder 1-5)
    Folder 1 contains a newsletter. Folders 2-3 contain files and photographs of the 2nd National Multicultural Conference and Summit held in Santa Barbara in 2001, where K. Patrick Okura received the Carolyn Attneave Award. Folder 5 contains a Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues (SPSSI) newsletter.
  - Special Services for Groups (SSG) general records, 1973-1994 (Box 43, Folder 6-8)
  - SSG - Pacific/Asian Elderly Services Resource Center, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    This contains an initial grant proposal.
  - SSG - National Pacific/Asian Elderly Resource Center, 1979 (Box 44, Folder 1-4)
    Includes annual proposal, Development Project reports, and regional workshop proceedings.
  - SSG - Asian American Drug Abuse Program (AADAP), 1981-2003 (Box 44, Folder 5-8)
    Folder 8 contains newsletters.
  - SSG - Japanese American (JA) Service Committee of Chicago, 1961 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - SSG - The Pacific/Asian American Mental Health Research Center, Chicago, 1974-1986 (Box 45, Folder 2-5)
    This was formerly known as the Asian American Mental Health Research Center. Folder 5 contains a Bay Area service directory.
  - SSG - Grant-supported advocacy programs, 1974-1997 (Box 45, Folder 6-7)
    This contains files on Coalition of Spanish-Speaking Mental Health Organizations and Woodley House.
  - SSG - National AA Psychology Training Center, 1979-1981 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - SSG - Smith, Kline & French continuing education, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 2-4)
    Folders 3-4 contain a 2 volume set of booklets and audiocassettes for Cultural Issues in Contemporary Psychiatry series.
  - SSG - Asian American/Pacific Islander (AAPI) community health advocacy organizations, 1974-1990 (Box 46, Folder 5-8)
    This includes materials on the National Asian Pacific American (APA) Advisory Committee, Native Hawaiian Drug Free Schools and Communities, Asian Pacific Islanders (API) Health Coalition, and Caucus of AA Health Workers.
  - SSG - AAPI community health advocacy organizations, 1981-2002 (Box 47, Folder 1-4)
    This includes materials on the AA Health Forum, National Asian Women's Health Organization, Pacific Rim Disease Prevention Center, and National AAPI Mental Health Association.
- Series 3: Appointments and consultancies files, 1972-2003
  The Appointments and consultancies files document work with the Maryland State Advisory Committee to U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, Maryland Public Schools of Montgomery County, Maryland Office of Human Rights of Montgomery County, National Mental Health Association (NMHA) Board of directors, Double "O" Associates, Horizon Health Group, Cosmos Corporation, Office for Substance Abuse Prevention (OSAP), and Center for Substance Abuse Prevention (CSAP).
  - Maryland (MD) State Advisory Committee to U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1981-1989 (Box 47, Folder 5-6)
  - MD State Advisory Committee to U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1989-1997 (Box 48, Folder 1-7)
  - MD State Advisory Committee to U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1997-2000 (Box 49, Folder 1-6)
  - MD State Advisory Committee to U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 2000-2003 (Box 50, Folder 1-5)
    This contains files on post-9/11 and Asian American (AA) civil rights issues.
  - MD State Advisory Committee to U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1992-2000 (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
    This contains files and newsletters on AA civil rights issues.
  - MD Public Schools, Montgomery County, 1990-1994 (Box 51, Folder 3-6)
  - MD Office of Human Rights, Montgomery County, 1995-2002 (Box 51, Folder 7-8)
    Folder 7 contains K. Patrick Okura's testimony on hate violence during a public hearing in November 1995. Folder 8 contains a Hall of Fame induction program.
  - MD Office of Human Rights, Montgomery County, 2002 (Box 191, Folder 1)
    This contains a Hall of Fame Plaque awarded to K. Patrick Okura for visionary leadership and diminishing effects of discrimination.
  - MD Office of Human Rights, Montgomery County, 1994-2001 (Box 52, Folder 1-5)
    This contains files on diversity, children, youth, and families. Folders 4-5 contains files on the AA Advisory Group for the Office of Human Resources.
  - National Mental Health Association (NMHA) - Board of directors, 1986-1997 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - NMHA - Board of directors, 1995-1998 (Box 53, Folder 1-7)
  - NMHA - Board of directors, 1996-2003 (Box 54, Folder 1-9)
    This contains committee meeting notes.
  - NMHA - Board of directors, 1997-2000 (Box 55, Folder 1-10)
  - NMHA - Board of directors, 1999-2002 (Box 56, Folder 1-9)
    This contains files on public affairs and strategic planning.
  - NMHA - Task forces, 1976-2001 (Box 57, Folder 1-11)
    This contains files on strategic planning and task forces on diversity and substance abuse.
  - NMHA - Task forces, 1986-2003 (Box 58, Folder 1-11)
    This contains media highlights and newsletters.
  - NMHA - Publications, 1986-1999 (Box 59, Folder 1-3)
  - Double "O" Associates, 1982-1993 (Box 59, Folder 4-9)
    This contains incorporation records, correspondence, and conference programs.
  - Horizon Health Group general records, 1982-1984 (Box 60, Folder 1-5)
    This contains files on the Institute for New Challenges.
  - Horizon Health Group general records, 1980-1984 (Box 61, Folder 1-9)
    This contains files on the Institute for New Challenges and international mental health collaborations. Folders 6-9 contains Sino-American Life Changes Stress study tour.
  - Horizon Health Group general records, 1972-1982 (Box 62, Folder 1-2)
    This contains files on the Sino-American Life Changes Stress study tour.
  - Substance Abuse Prevention - Cosmos Corporation, 1992-2000 (Box 62, Folder 3-5)
  - Substance Abuse Prevention - Office for Substance Abuse Prevention (OSAP), 1986-1990 (Box 62, Folder 6-9)
    This contains files on meetings, minorities, and programs. Folder 8 contains files on the Forum of California Asian American and Pacific Islander (AA&PI) Alcohol and Other Drug Concerns.
  - Substance Abuse Prevention - OSAP, 1989-1994 (Box 63, Folder 1-9)
    This contains community program files. Folders 7-9 contain Asian Pacific American (APA) High Risk Youth Cluster Group work files.
  - Substance Abuse Prevention - OSAP, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    This contains APA High Risk Youth Cluster Group files.
  - Substance Abuse Prevention - Center for Substance Abuse Prevention (CSAP), 1992-1994 (Box 64, Folder 2-9)
  - Substance Abuse Prevention - CSAP, 1989-1997 (Box 65, Folder 1-9)
    Folders 8-9 contain files on the National Prevention Network in connection with the National Association of State Alcohol and Drug Abuse Directors.
- Series 4: Community engagement files, 1930-2005
  The Community engagement files document work with civic and public advocacy organizations such as Asian and Pacific American Federal Employee Council, Asian/Pacific American Heritage Council (APAHC), Bradley Hills Presbyterian Church, National Japanese American Historical Society, National Asian Pacific American Legal Consortium (NAPALC), Organization of Chinese Americans, and the Urban League of Nebraska.
  - Civic - A-Ri-Rang Club, 1966-1968 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Civic - Asian American (AA) Business Roundtable, 1989-1991 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Civic - AA for Community Involvement, 1992-1994 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Civic - AA National Congress, 1990 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Civic - Asian American/Pacific Islanders in Philanthropy (AAPIP), 1992-2002 (Box 66, Folder 5-12)
  - Civic - Asian Benevolent Corps, 1975-1976 (Box 67, Folder 1-2)
  - Civic - Asian/Pacific American Heritage Council (APAHC), 1978-1991 (Box 67, Folder 3-10)
  - Civic - APAHC, 1979-1999 (Box 68, Folder 1-8)
  - Civic - APAHC, 1987-2002 (Box 69, Folder 1-6)
  - Civic - APAHC, 1998 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    This contains a commendation from President William J. Clinton for APA Heritage Month
  - Civic - Boy Scouts of America, 1930s (Box 69, Folder 7)
    This contains a circa 1930s photograph of Troop 379 posed with local officials at City Hall.
  - Civic - Bradley Hills Presbyterian Church, 1975-2000 (Box 69, Folder 8-11)
  - Civic - Bradley Hills Presbyterian Church, 1960-2003 (Box 70, Folder 1-9)
  - Civic - Bradley Hills Presbyterian Church, 1978-2005 (Box 71, Folder 1-6)
  - Civic - Los Angeles Old City Hall Gang, 1984-2002 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Civic - Fairview Presbyterian Church, 1953-1959 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Civic - Japan-America Student Conference (JASC), 1934 July 14-August 2 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    This contains an itinerary, opening ceremony program, domestic train tickets, and event information of the inaugural conference held in Japan.
  - Civic - JASC, 1934 (Box 183, Folder 3-5)
    This contains a newspaper scrapbook of the first conference.
  - Civic - JASC, 1934 (Box 221, Folder 1)
    This contains a photograph album of the first conference.
  - Civic - JASC, 1934 (Box 189, Folder 1-2)
    This contains an autograph book and presentation folding fan inscribed by conference attendees.
  - Civic - JASC, 1935 July 28-August 4 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    This contains a scrapbook on the second conference held at Reed College, Portland, OR. Also contains a 2002 letter penned by Rudie Wilhelm to Okura.
  - Civic - JASC, 1974-1983 (Box 71, Folder 10-12)
  - Civic - JASC, 1984-1985 (Box 72, Folder 1-2)
    This contains conference bulletins.
  - Civic - JASC, 1986-1994 (Box 72, Folder 3-8)
  - Civic - JASC, 1994-2001 (Box 73, Folder 1-9)
  - Civic - JASC, 2002-2003 (Box 74, Folder 1-2)
  - Civic - Japan-America exchange organizations, 1987-1996 (Box 74, Folder 3-4)
    This contains materials on the Joseph Heco Society and Manjiro Society.
  - Civic - Japanese American National Museum (JANM), 1987-1990 (Box 74, Folder 5-10)
  - Civic - JANM, 1991-1998 (Box 75, Folder 1-5)
  - Civic - Japanese American (JA) Veterans Association of Washington, D.C., 1963-2002 (Box 75, Folder 6-10)
  - Civic - Japanese University Club of Los Angeles, 1939-1941 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Civic - Japanese Young Men's Christian Association, 1939-1941 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Civic - National Institutes of Health AA Cultural Week, 1974-1975 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Civic - National Japanese American Historical Society (NJAHS), 1982-2002 (Box 76, Folder 2-7)
  - Civic - NJAHS, 1987 October 1 (Box 186, Folder 6)
    This contains an oversized, matted photograph taken at the opening ceremony of Smithsonian Institution's A More Perfect Union: Japanese Americans and U.S. Constitution exhibition.
  - Civic - National Japanese American Memorial Foundation (NJAMF), 1997-2000 (Box 76, Folder 8-11)
  - Civic - NJAMF, 1999-2000 (Box 183, Folder 6)
    This contains information on the groundbreaking dedication ceremony of the memorial.
  - Civic - Rotary Club of West Omaha, 1960-1972 (Box 77, Folder 1-2)
  - Civic - Southern California JA Savings Association, 1939-1941 (Box 183, Folder 7)
  - Civic - University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) Alumni Association, 1966-1997 (Box 77, Folder 3-6)
    This contains Board of Directors files.
  - Civic - UCLA Alumni Association, 1993-1994 (Box 78, Folder 1-3)
  - Civic - UCLA Alumni Association, undated (Box 203, Folder 14)
    This contains a brass belt buckle with the official seal of the University of California.
  - Civic - Asian American Studies Center (AASC), 1979-2005 (Box 78, Folder 4-9)
  - Civic - UCLA Athletics, 1934-2001 (Box 78, Folder 10-12)
    Folder 12 contains a donation to the Morgan Hall of Fame.
  - Civic - UCLA Bruin Caucus, 1994-1998 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Civic - UCLA Club of Washington, D.C., 1979-1991 (Box 79, Folder 1-2)
  - Civic - UCLA Psychology Club Alumni Association, 1930-2000 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    This also contains materials on the Psi Chi Society.
  - Civic - United Presbyterian Church of the USA, 1980-2003 (Box 79, Folder 4-6)
  - Civic - Voices of JA Redress Conference, 1997 (Box 79, Folder 7-8)
    This conference was sponsored by AASC.
  - Public advocacy - Asian and Pacific Americans (A&PA) Civil Rights Alliance, 1988 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Public advocacy - A&PA Federal Employees Council, 1975-1984 (Box 80, Folder 1-2)
  - Public Advocacy - Asian/Pacific American (APA) Coalition USA, 1992-1993 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Public Advocacy - APA Concerns Staff, 1977-1985 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    This includes materials on the Department of Education.
  - Public Advocacy - APA Democratic Caucus, 1980 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Public Advocacy - APA Institute for Congressional Studies, 1995-2000 (Box 80, Folder 6-8)
  - Public Advocacy - APAs for Norm Mineta, 1972-1984 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Public Advocacy - Asian Pacific Policy and Planning Council (A3PCON), 1982-2002 (Box 80, Folder 10-11)
  - Public advocacy - Democratic National Committee, 1994-2001 (Box 81, Folder 1-2)
  - Public advocacy - Division Office of AA Affairs, 1972-1979 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    This includes materials on the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.
  - Public advocacy - Federal APA Council, 1990-1991 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Public advocacy - National Alliance of APA Forum, 1979-1980 (Box 81, Folder 5-7)
  - Public advocacy - National Asian Pacific American Legal Consortium (NAPALC), 1990-1994 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Public advocacy - NAPALC, 1995-2001 (Box 82, Folder 1-4)
  - Public advocacy - Nisei Lobby, 1978 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    This is also known as Japanese American Advocates.
  - Public advocacy - Organization of Chinese Americans, 1979-1996 (Box 82, Folder 6-7)
  - Public advocacy - Parklawn Asian Federal Employees Community (PAFEC), 1975 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    This includes materials on the National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH).
  - Public advocacy - PAFEC, 1976-1982 (Box 83, Folder 1-2)
  - Public advocacy - Urban League of Nebraska, 1962-1971 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Public advocacy - White House, 1991-2000 (Box 83, Folder 4-8)
    These files contain efforts to establish an Office of Public Liaison Assistant to the President for A&PA "Asian and Pacific American Affairs."
- Series 5: Lily A. Okura files, 1941-2004
  The Lily A. Okura files document her work with the Young Women's Christian Association, C. Louis Meyer Therapy Center for Children, University of Nebraska Medical Center Volunteer Services, Corporation for Public Broadcasting (CPB), Altrusa Club, Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) Mountain Plains District Council, National Secretaries Association (NSA), and the Nebraska Welfare Association.
  - Professional Career - Young Women's Christian Association, 1941-1951 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Professional Career - C. Louis Meyer Therapy Center for Children, Omaha, 1955-1972 (Box 83, Folder 10-13)
    Folder 11 contains photographs of the groundbreaking ceremony. Folder 13 contains a handbook compiled by Lily Okura.
  - Professional Career - C. Louis Meyer Therapy Center for Children, Omaha, 1956-1968 (Box 84, Folder 1-4)
  - Professional Career - University of Nebraska Medical Center Volunteer Services, 1968-1993 (Box 84, Folder 5-6)
  - Professional Career - Corporation for Public Broadcasting (CPB), 1969-1982 (Box 84, Folder 7-11)
  - Professional Career - CPB, 1973-2002, undated (Box 85, Folder 1-12)
  - Professional Career - CPB, 1974-1982 (Box 86, Folder 1-7)
  - Professional Career - CPB, 1972-1988 (Box 91, Folder 14-15)
    This contains a curriculum vitae.
  - Civic Engagement - Altrusa Club of Omaha, 1963-1965 (Box 86, Folder 8-9)
  - Civic Engagement - Altrusa Club of Washington, D.C., 1974-2002 (Box 86, Folder 10-14)
  - Civic Engagement - Altrusa Club of Washington, D.C., 1979-2004 (Box 87, Folder 1-9)
    Folder 9 contains commendations.
  - Civic Engagement - Altrusa International District Two, 1986-2002 (Box 87, Folder 10-14)
  - Civic Engagement - Altrusa International District Two, 1991-2004 (Box 88, Folder 1-11)
  - Civic Engagement - Altrusa International District Two, 1974-2002 (Box 89, Folder 1-12)
  - Civic Engagement - Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) Mountain Plains District Council, 1953-1970 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Civic Engagement - JACL Mountain Plains District Council, 1972-1980 (Box 90, Folder 1-5)
    This contains materials on Lily Okura's JACL national vice presidency.
  - Civic Engagement - National Secretaries Association (NSA), 1954-1994 (Box 91, Folder 1-10)
  - Civic Engagement - NSA, 1954-1956 (Box 91, Folder 16)
    This contains a photograph album.
  - Civic Engagement - Nebraska Welfare Association, 1962-1969 (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Civic Engagement - News clippings, 1963-1987 (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - Civic Engagement - Commendations, 1962-1995 (Box 91, Folder 13)
- Series 6: Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) files, 1934-2004
  The Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) files contain National Board records, publications, research, and records of conventions, chapters, committees, and councils.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1964-1982 (Box 99, Folder 1-8)
  - National Board Records, 1981-2002 (Box 98, Folder 1-3)
    This contains a resolution for recognition and apology to Nisei resisters of conscience of World War II (WWII), and promotional leaflets, brochures, and pamphlets.
  - Washington Representatives, 1973-1981 (Box 98, Folder 4-6)
    This contains materials on Bill Marumoto, Wayne K. Horiuchi, and Ronald K. Ikejiri.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1936-1962 (Box 98, Folder 7-14)
  - National Board Records, 1975-2000 (Box 97, Folder 1-9)
    This contains work files, correspondence of past presidents, and building and legacy fund campaigns.
  - National Board Records, 1990-1997 (Box 96, Folder 1-7)
  - National Board Records, 1981-1990 (Box 95, Folder 1-8)
  - National Board Records, 1977-1982 (Box 94, Folder 1-6)
  - National Board Records, 1963-1999 (Box 93, Folder 1-12)
  - National Board Records, 1959-2000 (Box 92, Folder 1-12)
    This contains budget records, directories, and membership bulletins.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1938 September (Box 224, Folder 1)
    This contains a framed panoramic photograph of the 5th Biennial held in Los Angeles taken by LA Japanese Photo Studios Association.
  - International Relations National Committee, 1981, 1985 (Box 220, Folder 1)
    This contains a photograph album of the Pan American Nikkei Association Conference.
  - Washington, D.C. (WDC) Chapter community outreach photograph album, 1981 (Box 219, Folder 2)
    This contains materials on the Keiro-Kai Issei Senior Appreciation and Scholarship Dinner at Bradley Hills Presbyterian Church.
  - International Relations National Committee, 1971 (Box 219, Folder 1)
    This contains a photograph album of a national tour to Japan.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1938 September (Box 203, Folder 5)
    This contains a conference organizer ribbon with ornamental name tag for the 5th Biennial in Los Angeles, CA.
  - Los Angeles and other chapters in California, 1935 (Box 203, Folder 4)
    This contains a pioneer pin awarded to Inosuke Inose at the second annual Nisei Festival.
  - Los Angeles and other chapters in California, 1938 (Box 203, Folder 9)
    This contains a Nisei Week Queens Court pin.
  - Awards and Recognitions National Committee, undated (Box 203, Folder 6)
    This contains National Membership cufflinks.
  - Awards and Recognitions National Committee, undated (Box 203, Folder 7)
    This contains Membership Pins from the Thousand Club and the Century Club.
  - Awards and Recognitions National Committee, undated (Box 203, Folder 8)
    This contains National Membership pins and tie tack.
  - Awards and Recognitions National Committee, 1999 (Box 203, Folder 10)
    This contains a JACL 70th anniversary commemorative pin.
  - Awards and Recognitions National Committee, undated (Box 203, Folder 11)
    This contains a Ruby Pin in recognition of sacrifice and outstanding leadership and service to JACL.
  - Awards and Recognitions National Committee, undated (Box 203, Folder 12)
    This contains a Sapphire Pin in recognition of active loyalty to JACL for at least 10 years beyond one's own chapter activity.
  - Awards and Recognitions National Committee, undated (Box 203, Folder 13)
    This contains a Pearl Pin in recognition of chapter presidency.
  - National Board Records, 1975 July (Box 198, Folder 1)
    This contains a JACL National plaque that honors Okura for generosity and support of the first National Headquarters Building.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1964 July (Box 197, Folder 1)
    This contains a rolled panoramic photograph of the 18th Biennial held in Detroit, MI taken by Spencer Photographers.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1966 July (Box 197, Folder 2)
    This contains a rolled panoramic photograph of the 19th Biennial held in San Diego, CA taken by Carl G. Jorgensen.
  - District Council joint conventions, 1959 September (Box 195, Folder 1)
    This contains a rolled panoramic photograph of the Eastern and Mountain Plains district councils joint convention.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1954 September (Box 194, Folder 1-3)
    This contains a rolled panoramic photograph of the 13th Biennial held in Los Angeles, CA taken by Toyo Miyatake and King's Photo Service.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1944 (Box 193, Folder 1)
    This contains a rolled panoramic photograph of the 8th Biennial held in Salt Lake City, UT taken by Terashima Studio.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1952 June (Box 193, Folder 2)
    This contains a rolled panoramic photograph of the 12th Biennial held in San Francisco, CA taken by Utsumi Photos.
  - Biennial National Conventions, 1938 September (Box 192, Folder 1)
    This contains a rolled panoramic photograph of the 5th Biennial held in Los Angeles, CA.
  - Biennial National Conventions, undated (Box 192, Folder 2)
    This contains a rolled panoramic photograph.
  - Publications - Pacific Citizen, 1942-2002 (Box 188, Folder 1-9)
    This contains a Pacific Citizen newspaper.
  - Redress National Committee, 1994 (Box 187, Folder 3)
    This contains physical layouts and narrative of the War Relocation Authority (WRA) internment camps from 1942-1946, prepared by Takasumi Kojima for the teachers conference.
  - WDC Chapter Education Committee, undated (Box 186, Folder 7-8)
    This contains oversize display panels of Education: Speakers Bureau materials on mass detention camps for Japanese Americans (JA) from 1942-1946.
  - Aging and Retirement National Committee, 1988-1994 (Box 140, Folder 8-11)
    This contains work files on American Association of Retired Persons (AARP) minority affairs initiatives. Folder 11 contains presentation slides.
  - Publications - organizational literature, 1944 February (Box 140, Folder 1)
    This contains "Ben Kuroki's Story: an address by Sergeant Ben Kuroki" by the Commonwealth Club of San Francisco.
  - Publications - organizational literature, 1950, 1966 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    This contains Better Americans in a Greater America and the 1951 and 1966 reprints.
  - Publications - Pacific Citizen, 1964-1999 (Box 140, Folder 3-7)
    This contains Pacific Citizen newspaper files including President's Corner column by K. Patrick Okura, correspondence, and board reports.
  - Research for publication - Satow Memorial Fund, 1982 (Box 139, Folder 1)